Artur Vanivskyi - Software Developer

New York, NY | 646-830-9748 | vanivskyi.artur@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack software engineer proficient in using JavaScript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, API implementing, Node.JS, Express, PostgreSQL, and frameworks like Bootstrap. Problem solver with experience developing logical and methodical solutions to problems. A keen eye for design, allowing for the development of visually pleasing and user-friendly website designs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, jQuery.

Backend: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, GoLang.

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code.

Additional Skills: Ukrainian (fluent), Russian (fluent), Polish (Intermediate).

EXPERIENCE

Thinkful Remote

Full-Stack Engineering Student

06/2022 - 11/2022

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.
- Produced professional projects from concept to completion including:
 - E-commerce: Crown Shop | Project Link
 - Developed an e-commerce platform with user-friendly interface to provide customers with easy access to products, with focus on front-end development.
 - Implemented sign-in and google sign-in functionality.
 - Integrated a payment component using Stripe to enable customers to securely make transactions.
 - Used serverless functions to connect front-end and Firebase.
 - Utilized Redux Saga to maintain clean state management in an e-commerce platform.
 - Technology: JavaScript, React, Redux, CSS and FireBase, Stripe. Version control with Git.

• Movie Database Application | Project Link

- Assembled the back end of a movie website allowing any user to search for their favorite movies.
- Built an API following RESTful design principles.
- Used CRUD methods for reviews, and viewing theaters and movies that are showing.
- Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests and deployed the backend server to a cloud server.
- Technology: Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git.

• BusinessCard Holder "Vancard" | Project Link

- Full stack businesscard holder system.
- Originated and applied CRUD functions and queries to manage sending and retrieving data in database.
- Used Git to track changes while keeping sensitive information from being pushed to repositories.
- Programmed react router and express to build RESTful API.
- Technology: Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git.

• Restaurant Reservation System | Project Link

- Full stack reservation and table management system.
- Implemented react router and express to build a RESTful API in order to make HTTP requests for all of the reservation data stored on the connected PostgreSQL database.
- Created CRUD functions and Knex queries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
- Used Git to track changes while keeping sensitive information from being pushed to repositories.
- Technology: React, Node.js, Express, Knex and PostgreSQL.

- Study Tool Application | Project Link
 - Designed an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and cards within them.
 - Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow user(s) to create, read, update and delete.
 - Defined routes and URLs, and used state over multiple components.
 - Technology: JavaScript, React, Express, Knex, HTML, and CSS. Progress/Versions tracked with Git.

Masal / Masal Plus

Brooklyn, NY

Manager 04/2018 - 08/2022

- Formulated pricing policies by reviewing merchandising activities, and determined needed sales promotions.
- Completed store operational requirements by scheduling and assigning employees, and followed up on results.
- Maintained store staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training 40-50 employees.
- Prepared an annual budget and achieved financial objectives by saving an average of \$2500 per month.

GasInfoService

Ukraine

Online

Project Manager of Geology and Geophysics department

05/2016 - 08/2017

- Developed a database of various businesses which use and convey equipment used in the Geology and Geophysics surveys and closed 24 deals for the company, bringing in \$50K.
- Presented at conferences, pitching the company and its services, to gain new clients and partners.
- Built the structure for the web page in the Geology and Geophysics section, reviewing the JavaScript code.
- Introduced web-design for Geology and Geophysics section using Figma, Tailwind and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

Thinkful
Certificate, Software Engineering
AGH University of Science and Technology
MS, Applied Geophysics
Ivano-Frankivsk National Technical University of Oil and Gas
MS, Geophysics
Ivano-Frankivsk National Technical University of Oil and Gas
B.S, Geology

11/2022 Cracow, Poland 02/2017

Ivano-Frankivsk, Ukraine 02/2017 Ivano-Frankivsk, Ukraine

06/2015